today is the day
that we say goodbye
to the beautiful green mansion behind us
because today we are swapping bases
and part of me is relieved to not have
to work on this because i've been
putting off certain things for a little
while
the other half of me is actually kind of
worried because i'm moving into a base
that is way less finished than mine now
before we get into this swap i just want
to say that zf has absolutely free reign
over the mansion i am a-okay with
whatever he decides to do with the place
and it would be really good if we showed
him how awesome our community is and we
give him plenty of support during this
base swap so let's go and meet up with
zeddaff
and
let's talk terms
first of all
i need to figure out where his base is
every time i've found zeta space it's
been by accident i'm pretty sure it's
near tango's base but i'm not sure
oh that's his new name said zed
zed zed
swap time
you know what this is zed's problem now
this is zed's problem now oh oh oh oh i
better take that with me
just in case
grian my friend i guess i should start
off by welcoming you to my base
yes
it's awesome this is the bet one of the
best places on the server just got to
say thank you
thank you very much
oh is there anything i need to know
about this place any leaky pipes or
booby traps or anything like that
no 360 degrees finished all the way
around there's a bit of a mess which i'm
quite glad to be leaving behind like
there are just chests and shulker boxes
everywhere so if that annoys you it's
your problem now it's your mess good
luck oh boy i hadn't really looked at
the mess i'd kind of looked past that
and saw that i know
it is quite easy just to look past it i
just want to say that you are free to go
nuts and do whatever you want with the
sole exception of perhaps blowing the
whole thing up
right okay so don't make a tnt and
creeper powered with a farm yeah i'm
glad i said that because it sounds like
you were planning on blowing the whole
thing up
um i actually have i have one other
thing that i technically should show you
because i have two bases but um
i'm gonna have to show you kind of off
camera so if i if i can do it like a
three two one clap can we just cut to
cut to my my secret secret place yeah
okay
one two three
well here it is the giant diamond secret
base
we are that took us
so long to get here we are in cleo's
base now this doesn't belong to corrales
anymore so you own all of these diamonds
including pesky bird over here so please
feed him regularly what does he like uh
seeds
just any old seeds okay and blood
wow i'm staying away from pesky bird but
that's fine this is where it is okay i i
find this place by accident occasionally
but i've never been able to find it
directly so this is the front door this
is the literally the front door i
believe you stole it once or twice so
you should know talking about
literally in front of my eyes
it's true yeah you like with it do what
you like steal it as much as you need to
um so this is it the zf cave actually
the green cave now this is green's cave
of contraptions yeah um it's jam-packed
full of all the craziest wackiest
contraptions you your brain could ever
imagine so uh
be careful is my advice okay
okay
and i'm free to do whatever i want you
can pull any button any lever press
anything do whatever you like
buttons and levers
the thing right in front of you be very
careful about that is a void hole um
so
yeah down here
it takes you to the void no it doesn't
it will if you press that red button
what red button
the big red button oh there it is there
is
okay
just be careful of that a lot of things
can kill you a lot of things might break
slash explode or both i'm gonna have so
much fun here all right i guess i guess
that i guess good luck with with your
new mansion and thank you i've got some
work to do
okay i would shut the front door on my
way out but it's gone so
goodbye bye
okay
so we have officially inherited
zeddaff's base
and there's quite a lot going on in here
i've done a little bit of exploring and
i think i've understood
what all of these contraptions are or at
least i think i have this thing
is a very clever device that tells you
where the sun is and i think this is the
moon so if you let enough time pass it
should
i actually might go to that one there it
is there it is okay so yeah it tells you
where the sun is in the sky because of
course we are completely underground
this is a golf course i think
some sort of putting thing
take this
nailed it
look at that
absolutely amazing this is a device that
i haven't actually tried but i've been
itching to give a go i think that this
makes potions step one select how many
to brew
i guess that's three and then select
your potion type then look up
invisibility and
oh my goodness
it chucks it it chucks it in the that's
amazing okay
delivery method
nothing
is that it and it just brews it
this is incredibly clever when this hits
the bottom i think we're going to end up
with invisibility that's amazing that is
honestly amazing so what am i to do with
my new base this thing here is amazing
the magic puddle okay so in theory of
course you could just right click and
you end up with a water bucket right
well no not in zlata space in zf space
you throw the bucket in
and it throws
it's the most it's the most useless
machine
i've ever seen
but it's also amazing
it seems to me all of all of zf's
machines i suppose my machines just make
really simple tasks take a little bit
longer and i would love to add one of my
own to this contraption cave
but for now what i really want to do is
improve the cave itself i feel like it's
been excavated but not really a lot of
attention and look you can tell it's
night time there's the moon at the
moment so there's not been a huge amount
of attention done to the actual
excavation of this thing so i think i
want to open it up i want to try and
improve the look of the cave
and then i want it also to look i still
want it to look like a cave so
let's hop into a time lapse and work on
improving the general look of the cave
this is going to be a horrible thing to
work on by the way because
when you when you work on something
that's above you you gotta you gotta
scaffold up go up and yeah
it's it's not fun this is not it's not
it's not it's not a fun way to build
building things above you is never never
fun and this is going to take quite a
long time so
why don't we just get into it and try
and tidy up this cave a little bit just
a little bit
okay a few hours later and i have got
this place looking a little bit tidier
now one of the biggest things that you
will notice that's changed is these
support pillars that the cave just felt
like it was all unsupported it didn't
feel like it would normally hang the way
it was so i decided to add lots of these
supports everywhere just to make it feel
like this place would feel structurally
sound but this is not all that i have
planned you'll see that i left like this
little groove over here now my plans are
to have some minecarts going round and
i've also got a few more ideas for
detailing things so while i have made
some nice improvements in my opinion i
actually have a few more plans on how to
improve detailing wise i'm i'm thinking
there needs to be some more like rocks i
maybe even need some like holes that go
into the ceiling have some vegetation
growing down make this feel more organic
than it currently does it's very bland
it's it's all stone so i also need to
think about some texturing and things
like that but it is a start and that's
the main thing but it's not the only
thing that i worked on because you think
i was just going to leave the clio and
corrales game up to zf and everyone else
i i i am too excited about that so
we're gonna do it again one two three
that's right
we are back at the secret base but
obviously i don't own a secret base
anymore so i've made another secret base
and
it's a secret base attached to my old
secret base
oh man
it just it just keeps getting better
this way i'll still be able to
participate in the corrales games and i
thought we might be able to do something
in the city this episode so we can move
parts of the city into the sewer scare
corrales make him laugh add graffiti or
let's change this sign first so let's
have a look and see if there's something
we can do
over in the city i've come up with a
pretty good way
of i believe scaring cleo now i'm pretty
sure there's a high likelihood that she
will sit
in this here chair and if she doesn't
corrales will at some point it's just a
matter of time and in order to avoid
spoilers i'm gonna make sure that i
don't post this on my video until
someone has sat in the chair
ha i'm ahead of you you can't you can't
spoil everything so
here's the plan i gotta take everything
out of here first and what i'm thinking
we're gonna do
is make it so that when she sits here
she's gonna fall
and she's gonna fall
all the way
down and what will she find at the
bottom
well that's kind of the difficult part
i'm gonna have to try and trap four
creepers in here
so how do we get this to work well we're
gonna have to do a little bit of
reconfiguring
in order to make this work
and i'm actually pretty proud of myself
for this one because funny story i asked
impulse and etho to help me out with
this design
and it turns out it was a little bit
more tricky
than we initially thought
but we got there in the end and it was
actually me that came up with some old
redstone that made it all come together
it ended up being a very very
simple solution
so all we have to do is we hide this
pressure plate here when cleo stands on
it it's going to deactivate this
redstone torch which in turn
will power this piston
so everything is primed obviously it's
not all covered up yet but let's give
this a test run you sit in it activates
and you fall down
i took a little bit of damage and then a
creeper will blow i think one creeper is
probably enough for this i don't i don't
actually want her to lose any items or
anything and i'm scared if that there's
four creepers here
it it could be overkill maybe we should
go into another world and just test that
out because
yeah we don't want that to go wrong
right one creeper
for each side
she is gonna land right here man getting
these creepers here is not going to be
fun
let's try this with zero armor on
down we go
this is pretty much what she's going to
experience
uh i i didn't even get to the bottom
right we're not here to test if she dies
we're just here to test if she loses all
her items so let's try this again maybe
this time it'll work i've made a proper
tube this time
and here we go so this is pretty much
what she'll experience fall down
boom
yep
zero items left it's a good job we
tested that one creeper it is
we don't we don't want to risk anyone
losing their items i've had to do a few
refunds in the past and i tell you
they're not fun to do at all
so we're gonna have just the one creeper
right here i think we should rename
if we're going for a scare we're going
to rename the creeper to boo i never
really thought about it before but when
you say boo like when you call someone
boo it's kind of cute but if you shout
boo at someone it's meant to be scary
but it's it's still kind of cute so
boo boo boo boo's a terrible word for
what it's intended to do it doesn't work
i think i've talked myself out of not
doing it but we're going to do it right
let's set this thing up
and do one last test run
just to make sure
testing
and boom
okay
now all we need to do
is get ourselves
a creeper
and there we go
hey boo
how are you doing
suddenly by calling it boo it doesn't
seem so scary
hey boo how's it going ah there's a few
booze in here
all right come on
i need
ah
boo took out a boo yeah this is why this
is difficult all right there we go
that's the one come on
that's it
right you need to go
right here
oh no think about this think about this
okay the hole is right
what did i just see there's
there's no one online
there's something moving up there
you know that wasn't so bad
rename them to boo
right removing that glass is gonna be
the last thing that we need to do
so in theory it gets triggered
she falls down
and boom surprise
aha this is what was moving around up
here
all right let's get this thing primed
and ready the only noticeable difference
will be that there will be blue carpet
there instead of the gray it's the only
thing that might give this away
but let's just remember
that while corrales may be suspicious of
our antics
cleo almost certainly isn't
so the chairs that oh i nearly forgot
there was a banner
a diamond block
and another banner here
the torch is here to make sure that one
there's light
and two
the
white concrete powder disappears
so if i remove this
boo is activated
and we
are officially
out of here i've spent a long time
working all this out
let's pop the diamonds back in here
and i have a backup plan if this all
goes pear-shaped
so
the trap is set all we have to do now
is wait for cleo or corrales to come and
sit and see what happens if we get a
decent reaction i want some mega points
scaring scary glove is not an easy thing
i mean i've just spent an hour setting
up a stupid chair to fall so we'll see
what happens
but for now why don't we head back to
our base
and see what else we can do and what
else it has to offer
one thing is for sure
i may have tidied up the build but i'm
about to make this base
a proper green base just chests and
shulker boxes everywhere
it's uh it's just a bit of a hallmark
really i'm gonna build my new chest
monster here
so i was trying out a little design up
here and i think this could work really
nicely
so i want this to feel like a bit of a
suspended minecart bridge
obviously with this you can't actually
put a minecart on it but this is more
for the look than anything else so i
kind of want to have it suspended from
the ceiling
so let's do a small example run here and
see if we can get this looking good and
i think blackstone would probably work
better than cobblestone here but we'll
use that for the time being now if we
had a bunch of these and it all went
across the ceiling like this i think it
would look really really cool so now
i've built two of the hanging things i
think this works quite well it works
better attached to a wall instead of the
ceiling
however if i just change up some of
these torches
to be lanterns i think it gets lit up a
little bit better so let me just finish
this little test run to see if this
design works and run it into this wall
here and then we'll think about other
ways that we can kind of pretty this
place up
let's take a step back
and i think that's actually added quite
a lot of aesthetic to this place so
imagine more of this kind of thing
spread out throughout the cave so
imagine a real minecart system going
around there we'll have maybe one more
of these and maybe like a hole in the
roof as well so i think there's still
lots to do here i think one thing that
this base really could use
is a proper entrance it could really use
just
something to call it the front of the
base because this this door that someone
stole
is uh
it's not quite good enough because i
think this base has an awful lot of
potential
and i think if we can come up with stuff
that keeps the sort of wacky crazy
contraption theme we will be able to
make something that looks absolutely
amazing in here and also i found out
there's a little secret thing up here
there's a giant green house which i saw
from the outside but i didn't realize
you could easily get in from the inside
there's like this greenhouse type thing
so
there's also
i'm not quite sure what this is i'm
pretty sure it's alive i'm not quite
sure what this does
but i'm feeling like we could make good
use of this by adding some really nice
greenery and make this feel more like a
real greenhouse as i explore this base
i'm finding more and more things there's
just secret pressure plates that bring
up
clothes i think and then buttons that
make them go down again which is pretty
cool i mean i don't have different sets
of armor so i mean this is pretty rad
and the the deeper you go into the cave
i don't even know what this is
i
haven't quite figured this one out i
really
i'm really not sure what this one does
there's still a few things to figure out
like
the purpose of the jump powered furnace
this has got to be the slowest furnace
that's ever existed but i've been having
a lot of fun
figuring out what everything does
so this has been my first day at my new
base i think i might have an idea on how
to get the mansion back but first i
think we should just enjoy our time here
and perhaps finish improving the base
before we look at even trying to swap
back because i don't know it's been a
nice breath of fresh air working on a
different project which i've just had no
input on whatsoever and just
coming in and just improving it in
whatever way i can so this has been a
lot of fun so far and i've got to see
this project through if you have any
ideas for what we could do here do let
me know i don't want to take away the
essence of the base that's the main
thing i don't want to take away any of
the contraptions i don't want to build
around them i want to keep everything
that's there i just want to tidy up a
few things but there might be something
really drastic that i'm missing i want
to add an entrance some pathways and
some more detailing bits like this but
for now i think we've run out of time we
actually got quite a lot done we did a
lot of improvements in the new base and
we set up a trap which when this goes
live you will know has been triggered
so thank you very much for watching i
hope you enjoyed this video please do
consider leaving a comment to let me
know what else we can do here and if you
enjoyed it please do consider
subscribing and i shall see you in the
next episode good bye